Preliminary Inventory to the Germany. Reichskanzlei. Adjutantur des Führers Records, 1934-1944
Hoover Institution Archives
Germany. Reichskanzlei. Adjutantur des Führers Records,
1934-1944
XX353
Germany. Reichskanzlei. Adjutantur des Führers
3 manuscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, personnel records, and miscellanea, relating to the German economy, military activities of the Schutzstaffel (SS) Begleitkommando, and miscellaneous administrative matters.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945.; Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei. Schutzstaffel. Begleitkommando; National socialism; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945 Germany; Germany; Germany--Economic conditions--1918-1945; Germany--Politics and government--1933-1945
Preliminary Inventory
- Assistant to the Fuhrer, Herrn Hauptmann a D. Wiedemann. Miscellaneous file, 1933-1938 (Box 1.)
- Assistant to the Fuhrer, Herrn Hauptmann a. D. Wiedemann. Miscellaneous file, 1933-1938 (Box 2.)
- Report. "The conclusion of the inquiries of the state secret police against Dr. Banasch and others concerning treason, 1935 December 17
- Miscellanea concerning Austria, 1936
- Italo-Ethiopian War, 1936
- Mail record, 1940 May-August
- Reichsminister Darre, 1935-1936
- Haubensack, Otto Dr., 1935-1939
- Steinbrecher, Ilse Dr., 1935 (Box 3.)
- von Schmude, Ernst, 1934-1943
- Kolb, Richard, 1938-1939
- SS Begleitkommando, 1943-1944
- Sprechstellen-Verzsichnis. Anlage Berghof. 1944